Akshit Madan

Email: akmadan17@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 8669164552

STATEMENT

A Fullstack Software Engineer with expertise in developing and managing AI based client/server side modules. I am also a Tech Content Creator @YouTube with 40K subscribers where I published 300+ tutorials in the domains of Software Development and Management. My past experience of being a Founding Engineer and a Team Lead adds to my skills of designing solutions from scratch.

EDUCATION

PICT, BE in Computer Engineering Aggregate CGPA: 9.54

Dhankawadi, Pune 2019-2023

SKILLS

- Concepts: OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms, RAG, Finetuning LLMs, websockets, webRTC, System Design and Microservices Concepts
- Languages: Dart, Python, Typescript
- Frontend: Flutter SDK (BLoC, Clean Architecture, TDD)
- Backend/Databases: NodeJS/ExpressJS, FastAPI, Flask, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Pinecone, Prisma, TypeORM
- Software Tools: Linux, Git/Github, Postman, Cloudflare, Docker, Kubernetes, various AWS Tools, Bitrise CI/CD, Langchain, LlamaIndex and various Python libraries for Data Science and NLP.
- Management: Founding Engineer @Resumepal Leading the team of Tech and Business Developers

EXPERIENCE

• Resumepal AI

Founding Engineer

Pune, India
Jan 2024 - Present

- o Role: : Architecing the AI based solution for Talent Tech
- Work: As the Founding Engineer at Resumepal, I am responsible for architecting and implementing the core software module. My current project involves developing a RAG-based Mock Interview Platform, utilizing sophisticated natural language processing and facial expression analysis algorithms to enhance user interactions and feedback mechanisms

Azodha Inc.

Pune, India

Mobile Team Lead

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

- \circ Role: : To Lead the team of Developers focused on Mobile App Projects
- Work: As the Team Lead at Azodha, I developed a Multi-Level Architecture for our mobile projects, standardizing the structure across all Frontend Projects. This architecture detailed the interaction between various software layers, emphasizing module reusability. Additionally, I extensively utilized the WebSockets protocol to enhance real-time communication in one of our key projects.

Tickertape (smallcase)

Bengaluru, India

Software Development Intern (Flutter)

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

- o Team: : Tickertape Mobile Dev Team
- Work: : Being a part of Mobile Development Team, I worked with BLoC State Management, MVC Architecture, advanced Dart concepts and plugins, integrated APIs, understood CI/CD lifecycle, sending user Analytics to cloud server. Following a particular Software Design Pattern is my biggest take from this internship.

PROJECTS AND PUBLICATIONS

• Converting Epics/Stories into Pseudocode Using Transformers (Published in 2023 IEEE 20th India Council International Conference (INDICON)): The conversion of user epics or stories into their appropriate representation in pseudocode or code is a time-consuming task, which can take up a large portion of the time in an industrial project. With this research paper, we aimed to present a methodology to generate pseudocode from a given agile user story of small functionalities so as to reduce the overall time spent on the industrial project

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Youtuber: : Delivered 450+ Videos regarding Industry Level App and ML Projects on YouTube. Served multiple International App Development Clients. My tutorials cover topics like Flutter, Backend Frameworks, NLP and Kaggle Dataset Analysis
- Winner: Solveathon by Cognizant: : Proposed a Solution on Social Distancing Management in Public Places using Computer Vision and Deep Learning
- First Runner Up: MindSpark by CoEP: Created a Digital Medicine Prescription System, Doctors, Patients and Pharmacist all on a single platform.
- Second Runner Up: Pasckathon by PICT, ACM: Created an EMF Recording App that sends data to cloud for generating Density and Heatmap Plots.